## Tomasz Klosinski

DevOps / System Engineer

+33 755 77 37 37

tomasz.klosinski@protonmail.ch

For detailed list of projects visit: linkedin.com/in/tklosinski

I am a passionate Linux Engineer with 4 years experience in server automation and configuration management. My current position is System Engineer in DevOps and Infrastructure teams at CERN Control Center.

#### Competencies

- # Linux, Bash
- # Ansible, Python,
- # Docker, Vagrant, Jenkins
- # Cloudera Hadoop
- # OpenStack, Amazon Web Services
- # Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

#### Areas of Interest

- # Continuous Integration/Delivery
- # Big Data, Cloud Computing, IT Infrastructure
- # Agile Methodologies

## Education

2010-2012

Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology

Databases, M.A.

2008-2011

University of Lodz

Business Management, B.A.

2007-2010

University of Lodz

Computer Science, B.A.

### Cerification

- Red Hat Certified Engineer
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator

## Languages

- Polish (Native)
- English (C1)
- French (A2)

# Experience

CERN (Geneva) System Engineer 04/2015-03/2016

- (1) System Administration Modernisation Project
  - Support and troubleshooting of over 2800 OpenStack VMs, desktops and servers critical to the operation of CERN accelerators.
  - Transformation of an old bash/awk/Python script-based configuration management to a modern Ansible-based solution.
  - Replacement of inconsistent/non-existing version control of various parts of system configuration with a single git tree.
  - Massive analysis, comparison, fixing errors and making more consistent of kickstart files for 2800+ machines (included also changes in PXE servers and generating kickstart files based on Ansible inventory file and CERN's internal sources of data about hosts).
  - Implementing a filesystem monitoring system based on auditd, rsyslog, Elasticsearch, Logstash/Logalike and Kibana (dashboards).
  - Creating monit configuration for process management and monitoring.
  - Developing dozens of Ansible playbooks for configuration of various aspects of OS and applications.

- (2) Process Management and Deployment Project (PoC)
  - Design and implementation of the platform that could replace the former legacy service management solution, while keeping the interface and release-deploy-configure workflow for users backward compatible.
  - Development of Python and Ansible-based tool for:
    - deployment of the accelerators controls applications;
    - adding/removing the services to/from an applications database (to make them persistent across OS reinstallations);
    - generating configuration for service monitoring and management (based on monit);
    - providing a consistent solution for supplying user specific (monit) checks for a service or group of services.
- (3) Accelerator Project Exploitation Tools Tracing
  - $\bullet \ \ System \ administration \ of \ Elasticsearch/Logalike/Kibana \ clusters:$ 
    - upgrade to ES 2.0 and Kibana 4;
    - creation of nginx reverse proxy configuration;
    - creation of monit configuration and checks for all ELK services;
    - writing a Logalike extension in Java 8.

### LINUX POLSKA (Warsaw)

Solution Architect

02/2014-03/2015

- (1) Open Source Day
  - Organization of the biggest Open Source event in Poland.
- (2) EuroLinux Project
  - Design and implementation of Automated Delivery Pipeline for building RPM packages (using bash scripts chained into Jenkins' jobs):
    - building RPM packages with open source tools (from Fedora Project): koji, mock, mash/createrepo, revisor/pungi, Sigul;
    - maintenance and configuration of Jenkins, GitLab, git repositories, etc;
    - development of bash and Python scripts;
    - configuration of testing environment based on Vagrant, Packer, RHEV's virtual machines;
    - set up of Zabbix monitoring.

### IMPAQ GROUP (Warsaw)

Software / System Engineer

11/2011-01/2014

- Support of RHEL/Oracle/Java telco applications for international cellular networks.
- Installation of a OpenStack cluster integrated with a GlusterFS cluster (automated with Chef).
- Development of Chef cookbooks for automatic orchestration of development and testing environments of Java web applications (+Apache Tomcat and Oracle XE 11g).
- Installation, configuration (using Chef) and maintenance of the Hadoop cluster and additional tools.
- Marketing and pre-sales activities for M2M, Cloud Computing and Big Data Business Practice.
- Design and implementation of the Linux services infrastructure in mVoip project:
  - load balancing and HA mode: HAProxy and nginx;
  - MySQL Master-Master Semisynchronous Replication cluster and Apache Cassandra cluster.
  - Zabbix monitoring and syslog-ng centrallized logging;
  - Jira OnDemand administration